Yuanqi Du

♀ 10316 Tracie Ann Ct, Fairfax, VA

☑ ydu6@gmu.edu ☐ (1)202-751-8773 ♣ https://yuanqidu.github.io/

SUMMARY

Undergraduate researcher trained in artificial intelligence, with strong communication skills developed from extensive research experience and ability to work independently or as part of a team. Special expertise in the following areas: **Interpretable Machine Learning**; **Deep Graph Learning**; **Deep Generative Models**; **ML for Sciences** (Biology/Chemistry/Physics).

EDUCATIONS

George Mason University

B.S. in Computer Science

GPA: 4.0/4.0 | Major: 16/18 A+

Huaqiao University *B.S. in Computer Science*

GPA: 4.67/5.00

Fairfax, VA

Aug 2017 - May 2021

Xiamen, China

Aug 2016 - Jun 2017

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Papers

- Xiaojie Guo, **Yuanqi Du**, Liang Zhao. Property Controllable Variational Autoencoder via Invertible Mutual Dependence, accepted in ICLR 2021 conference.
- Pengbo Liu, Hu Han, **Yuanqi Du**, Heqin Zhu, Yinhao Li, Feng Gu, Honghu Xiao, Jun Li, Chunpeng Zhao, Xinbao Wu, S. Kevin Zhou, Deep Learning to Segment Pelvic Bones: Large-scale CT Datasets and Baseline Models, accepted in IPCAI 2021 conference, published in IJCARS journal.
- Panneer Selvam Santhalingam, Yuanqi Du, Riley Wilkerson, Al Amin Hosain, Ding Zhang, Parth Pathak, Huzefa Rangwala, and Raja Kushalnagar. Expressive ASL Recognition using Millimeterwave Wireless Signals. IEEE International Conference on Sensing, Communication and Networking (SECON) 2020.
- Yuanqi Du, Nguyen Dang, Riley Wilkerson, Parth Pathak, Huzefa Rangwala, Jana Kosecka. American Sign Language Recognition Using an FMCW Wireless Sensor. AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020 (Student Abstract).

Journal Papers

• Taseef Rahman, **Yuanqi Du**, Amarda Shehu. Generative Adversarial Learning of Protein Tertiary Structures, accepted in Molecules [impact factor: 3.267] journal.

Workshop Papers

- Yuanqi Du, Xiaojie Guo, Amarda Shehu, Liang Zhao. Interpretable Property Controlling Molecule Generation. AAAI 2021 Scientific Discovery with AI (SDA) Workshop, Oral Presentation.
- Yuanqi Du, Xiaojie Guo, Amarda Shehu, Liang Zhao. Interpretable Molecule Generation via Disentanglement Learning. ACM Conference of Bioinformatics and Computational Biology (BCB) Workshops: Computational Structural Biology Workshop (CSBW) 2020.
- Yuanqi Du, Xiaojie Guo, Amarda Shehu, Liang Zhao. From Interatomic Distances to Protein Tertiary Structures with a Deep Convolutional Neural Network. ACM Conference of Bioinformatics and Computational Biology (BCB) Workshops: Computational Structural Biology Workshop (CSBW) 2020.

PREPRINTES & WORKING PAPERS

- Yuanqi Du, Xiaojie Guo, Amarda Shehu, Liang Zhao. Controllable Molecular Graph Generation via Monotonic Constraints, submitted to KDD 2021 conference.
- Yuanqi Du, Quan Quan, Hu Han, S. Kevin Zhou. Where is the disease? Semi-supervised pseudo-normality synthesis from an abnormal image, submitted to MICCAI 2021 conference.
- Xiaojie Guo*, **Yuanqi Du***, Liang Zhao. Disentangled Representation Learning for Spatial Graph via Information Bottleneck, submitted to KDD 2021 conference.
- Yuanqi Du, Xiaojie Guo, Amarda Shehu, Liang Zhao. Disentangled Representation Learning for Interpretable Molecule Generation, submitted to Molecules journal.
- Runsheng Xu*, Zhengzhong Tu*, **Yuanqi Du***, Xiao Yu, Jinlong Li, Zibo Meng, Hongkai Yu. OldNet: Renovate the Old Memories, submitted to ACM MM 2021 conference.
- Quan Quan, Qiyuan Wang, Liu Li, Yuanqi Du, S. Kevin Zhou, CT Film Recovery via Disentangling Geometric Deformation and Photometric Degradation: Simulated Datasets and Deep Models, arXiv preprint arXiv:2012.09491 (2020).
- Yuanqi Du, et al. trPredictor: Transformer-based Protein Tertiary Structures Predictor from Interresidue Contacts, going to submit to Bioinformatics journal.
- Yuanqi Du, et al. Disentangled Inductive Learning on Spatial-temporal Graphs, going to submit to NeurIPS 2021 conference.

PROFESSIONAL & RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Microsoft Research Asia Beijing, China

Research Intern (Machine Learning & Computational Biology Group) Nov 2020 - Expected May 2021

Topic: Protein Structure Prediction, Advisor: Jianwei Zhu

Emory University

Research Assistant

Sep 2020 - Present

Topic: Deep Graph Learning and Applications, Advisor: Liang Zhao

Chinese Academy of Sciences Beijing, China

Research Intern (MIRACLE Group)

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

Topic: Medical Image Analysis, Advisors: S. Kevin Zhou, Hu Han

George Mason University

Research Assistant

Fairfax, US

Jan 2020 - Apr 2021

Topic: Learning Protein Structures and Dynamics, Advisor: Amarda Shehu

George Mason University Fairfax, US

Research Assistant Apr 2019 - May 2020

Topic: Application of Milimeter-wave Radar Signals, Advisor: Parth Pathak

TEACHING & MENTORING EXPERIENCES

George Mason University
Student Research Mentor
Fairfax, US
Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

Topic: Education Data Mining with Focus on Student Performance Prediction

Published a research paper, titled Ensemble Machine Learning System for Student Academic Performance Prediction, in W4LL workshop @FDM 2021

mance Prediction, in W4U workshop @EDM 2021.

George Mason University

Fairfax, US

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

Courses: Object-oriented Programming, Data Structures, Data Mining

George Mason University Fairfax, US

Peer Mentor Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

Courses: Engineering Courses & Careers Services

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

- Reviewer for KDD 2021
- Co-organize DLG 2021, co-located with KDD 2021 (Web Co-chair, PC)
- Co-organize DeepSpatial 2020/2021 co-located with KDD 2020/2021 (Web/Publicity Chair)
- BioKDD 2021 (PC)
- Co-organize KDD 2021 (Web Team)
- Co-organize AAAI 2021 (STudent Technical Volunteer)
- Contribute to the open-source community (e.g. DeepChem)

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

NeurIPS, AIJ AIIDE Travel Award	2020
NSF REU Fellowship	2019-2020
Distinguished Undergraduate Research Award	2019-2020
Distinguished Undergraduate Teaching Assistant Award	2019-2020
GMU OSCAR Fellowship	Summer 2019
Outstanding Undergraduate Teaching Award	2018-2019

VOLUNTEERS & LEADERSHIPS

- Vision Organization, Founder
- Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador (Organized Intro to AI and ML workshop)
- Student Member of ACM, IEEE, IEEE Computer Society, AAAI, SIAM, ASA Community
- GMU SCAN (Career) Mentor, 2021 Spring
- Activities: NetBrain Club Research Director

MISCELLANEOUS

 Coursera Certificates: Machine Learning; Deep Learning; Deep Neural Network with PyTorch; Probabilistic Graphical Models;